<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Agile Techies Daily List</title>
    <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Agile Techies Daily List</description>
    <image>
      <title>The Agile Techies Daily List</title>
      <url>https://agiletechies.com/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://agiletechies.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thirty Computers in the Room</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/software-is-everywhere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/software-is-everywhere/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Look around now - how many computers are in the room?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I count about thirty. Phones, the TV, my dyson heater, my headset, my oura ring, remote controls : nearly everything with a button on it runs software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That matters because &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; one of those devices needs code written by teams likes yours. Software touches law, health, transport, and food systems. And small mistakes can cascade into real harm. As software builders, we must treat our craft as responsible work: design carefully, test relentlessly, and assume our code has consequences beyond the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upping Our Game: Professionalism</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/professionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/professionalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile development prizes discipline over ceremony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a promise to raise our craft and to foster professional behavior across all aspects of software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen teams ship junk, and just casually accept defects, and make poor lazy trade-offs. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising to see some of those habits being tolerated at some organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want respect for our work, quality and discipline must be nonnegotiable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discussions for your team&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we being professional and constantly finding opportunities to pair, clean out tech debt, and refactor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do our cycles produce quality (almost) bug free output each time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What practices are we following to prevent unsafe or low-quality releases?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are we guiding our team to continually improve our level of professionalism?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Programming</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/extreme-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/extreme-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the agile processes, Extreme Programming (XP) is the clearest, most complete, and least muddled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many other software developerment approaches that were invented afterwards are a subset of - or a variation on XP. I don’t dismiss those approaches; some fit specific projects types. But when I want my builders to learn what the original agile software development approach was about, I point them to XP as a great template to start with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Business Value Order</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/business-value-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/business-value-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to stop wasting time building the wrong thing. Every iteration ask the stakeholders,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;what should we build next?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They answer in business-value order, and we implement in that order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, features have dependencies — we&amp;rsquo;re builders; we handle them. The point is simple: let stakeholders decide priority so the team can focus on delivering value. When stakeholders say a feature is low value, we don&amp;rsquo;t build it yet. When they point to something critical, we give it attention first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When &#34;All of it by New Year&#34; Meets the Data</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/when-all-of-it-by-new-year-meets-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/when-all-of-it-by-new-year-meets-the-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever had the project stakeholders demand everything by a fixed date?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tell them plainly — &lt;em&gt;if you want every feature, the timeline will stretch.&lt;/em&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t argue; Show the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When stakeholders insist, ask them to choose: accept a later date or reduce scope. In rational organizations the numbers win: teams deliver what&amp;rsquo;s prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Help the stakeholders &lt;em&gt;scrutinize&lt;/em&gt; the plan, identify what truly must ship by the deadline, and gently defer the rest. It hurts to drop features, but real choices beat false promises.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Go Fast by Going Well</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/go-fast-by-going-well/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/go-fast-by-going-well/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to finish is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to cut corners — it&amp;rsquo;s to raise the bar on quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick‑and‑dirty doesn&amp;rsquo;t speeds things up. &lt;strong&gt;Trash code, missing tests, skipped reviews - they slow the team down.&lt;/strong&gt; When technical debt accumulates, every change takes longer, bugs multiply, and momentum dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead do things well: keep tests in the flow, do reviews, refactor relentlessly, and protect sustainable work practices. These habits look slower at first, but they pay back quickly in reduced rework and faster, safer delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Should We Add More Builders?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/should-we-add-more-builders/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/should-we-add-more-builders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Piling in fresh people onto a late project is rarely the quick fix managers hope for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brooks&amp;rsquo; Law is real:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;adding manpower to a late project makes it later.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When new people arrive, productivity usually plunges while the team absorbs them. Veterans spend time teaching instead of building, and team recovery is slow moving - if it does at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiring can help over the long haul, but as a fast remedy it&amp;rsquo;s a gamble. Often budgets won&amp;rsquo;t allow more staff, so the practical levers are &lt;strong&gt;scope, quality,&lt;/strong&gt; and how the current team works together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kill The Hope</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/kill-the-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/kill-the-hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s our job to &lt;em&gt;kill dangerous hope early&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hope&lt;/strong&gt; lets teams give optimistic answers that hide real progress. That&amp;rsquo;s how projects quietly fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead we should aim to gather hard data every iteration so managers, product owners, and stakeholders can make real decisions instead of wishful guesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t about going faster - it&amp;rsquo;s about learning the truth as soon as possible so we can &lt;strong&gt;manage&lt;/strong&gt; trade‑offs effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delivering hard facts quickly gives us options; clinging to hope removes them. I encourage teams to treat iteration feedback as a tool for making pragmatic, timely choices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rhythm Not A Sequence</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/rhythm-not-sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/rhythm-not-sequence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile development isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;Waterfall sliced into smaller pieces&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too often we treat iterations like mini-projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis at the start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding in the middle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing at the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that&amp;rsquo;s not Agile — that&amp;rsquo;s Waterfall on shuffle mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In true Agile development, &lt;strong&gt;requirements, architecture, design, and implementation happen continuously throughout the iteration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learn → adjust → build → validate → repeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This flow isn&amp;rsquo;t a sequence — it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;rhythm&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YAGNI – You Aren&#39;t Gonna Need It (Yet!)</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/yagni-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/yagni-yet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When starting a project, it’s tempting to grab every shiny tool—MongoDB, Kafka, React, Terraform. But each one adds cost: learning, debugging, lock‑in, maintenance, and version headaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cheapest tool?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not using it. (Yet!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;start-simple&#34;&gt;Start Simple&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Begin with the plainest possible solution. Before installing a database, ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can text files work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can a folder of binaries work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can an in‑memory map power the prototype?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, you can go surprisingly far without extra tools. And when you finally need one, you’ll choose it based on real needs—not guesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Teams Don&#39;t Split Huge Stories</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/why-teams-dont-split-huge-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/why-teams-dont-split-huge-stories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A team creates a user story for a full calendar feature. The PO, BA, UX, and accessibility SME add pages of detail so developers have everything they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developers see the ticket, they know it’s far too big. It needs splitting—but rewriting all that detail feels time‑consuming, inconvenient, and no one volunteers to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the team decides to work on the giant story as-is and &amp;ldquo;figure out the rest later.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Your Team Avoid Updating Code Comments?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/does-your-team-avoid-updating-code-comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/does-your-team-avoid-updating-code-comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something to discuss with your team:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re working on a ticket, deep in your own task. Then you notice something odd: in a completely unrelated part of the codebase, the comments don&amp;rsquo;t match what the code actually does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe someone changed the logic earlier but forgot to update the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now imagine this was your &lt;strong&gt;solo project&lt;/strong&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;d probably just fix the comment right away. Write a quick update, commit it, done. How long would that take? A couple of minutes, maybe?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Runaway Process Inflation</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/runaway-process-inflation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/runaway-process-inflation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hidden-cost-of-too-much-process&#34;&gt;The Hidden Cost of Too Much Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen many teams fall into the trap of &lt;em&gt;Runaway Process Inflation&lt;/em&gt;.  They start with simple workflows, then gradually adding more steps in the name of efficiency. Yet each new step can subtly slow delivery instead of helping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More process doesn’t always mean more effectiveness.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before adding a checklist, approval, or workflow gate, consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this help us deliver working software faster?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it speed up feedback or slow it down?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it improve decisions or just add paperwork?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we solving a real issue or simply creating the illusion of control?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-essential-question&#34;&gt;The Essential Question&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How will this affect our ability to get changes in front of customers?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Makes The Velocity Chart Useful</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/useful-velocity-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/useful-velocity-chart/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Velocity Chart records how many story points are completed in each iteration sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an important chart to have, and I recommend it to all my clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the team creates user stories, they are added to the backlog. At some point, those stories need to move into the current sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how many stories should we move into the sprint? We won’t know until we’ve done some basic estimations to get an idea of how many we should pull from the top of the backlog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Velocity Chart Problem</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/velocity-chart-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/velocity-chart-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Velocity Chart records how many story points are completed during each iteration sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an important chart to have, and I recommend it to all my clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that many teams use this chart incorrectly. They try to use it to measure how much work the team should aim to complete in the next sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the sprint, this can create pressure on the team to work faster to meet that objective (often by secretly compromising on quality). Alternatively, it can cause the team to slow down and stretch their work pace so that their last bit of work aligns with the sprint end date. This way, they avoid closing all their tickets and being left with nothing to report in the daily meeting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Management (Taylorism)</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/scientific-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/scientific-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before we had the light-weight agile type of development approaches there were two modes of thinking about how software should be built.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light-weight approach (agile before it was called “agile”) worked well for projects that enjoyed a low cost of change, and solved partially defined problems with informally specified goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other perspective was more aligned with “Scientific Management” which worked best for projects that suffered a high cost of change and solved very well-defined problems with extremely specific goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sprint Or Marathon?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/sprint-or-marathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/sprint-or-marathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not particularly fond of the term &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;sprint&amp;rdquo; often gives the impression that the team needs to prioritize on working as fast as possible. And inadvertently creates pressure to complete every user story before the end of the sprint, sometimes at the expense of quality, or by allowing technical debt to build up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, agile development is more like a marathon, where we maintain a healthy, steady, sustainable pace. It’s not a relay race where teams sprint as fast as they can, trying not to drop the baton at the end of each leg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which Projects Work Well With Agile?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/which-projects-work-well-with-agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/which-projects-work-well-with-agile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agile works well for projects that have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A low cost of change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems that are discovered along the way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Informally specified goals, that could alter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more traditional approach might be a better option when:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of change is high.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The complete set of problems are known up-front.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goals are very specific and fully understood from the start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iron Triangle</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/iron-triangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/iron-triangle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have heard of the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Iron Cross&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Have you heard of the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Iron Triangle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality (Deliver what&amp;rsquo;s expected. And account for all of the exceptional scenarios flows)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope (How much stuff is delivered)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resources (Time, brains, tools, dollars, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pick any two, and the third is a variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inevitably, we will want “Quality” to be maxed out. So, we can only focus on “Scope” or “Resources.” If we want a larger scope of work completed, we need to increase the resources. Alternatively, if resources are fixed, we must accept and define how much scope of work we can realistically complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Iron Cross</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/iron-cross/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/iron-cross/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have heard of the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Iron Cross&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good&lt;/strong&gt; (Quality)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Delivered) &lt;strong&gt;Fast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheap&lt;/strong&gt; (Under budget)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(Everything) &lt;strong&gt;Done&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on any three you like, but you can’t have the fourth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can have a project that is &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; quality, delivered on time &lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt;, and within budget and &lt;strong&gt;cheap&lt;/strong&gt;. But! not everything will get &lt;strong&gt;done&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, you can have a project that is all &lt;strong&gt;done&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;cheap&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;fast&lt;/strong&gt;, but it won’t be &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt; quality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Elephant in the Room: Agile Workflow Incompatibility</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/elephant-in-the-room-agile-workflow-incompatibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/elephant-in-the-room-agile-workflow-incompatibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to not assume that the software your team is working is compatible with an agile workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile is about &lt;em&gt;embracing change&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for that to happen, the software itself needs to be intentionally designed with adaptability in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve joined many teams where the management and scrum master were on-board with following an agile approach, but they were   completely oblivious to the fact that the software being built wasn&amp;rsquo;t compatible with an agile workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Happened to The Agile Movement?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/what-happened-to-the-agile-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/what-happened-to-the-agile-movement/</guid>
      <description>Uncle Bob explains how Agile was originally a movement invented by developers</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is the Agile Software Development Approach?</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/what-is-the-agile-software-development-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/what-is-the-agile-software-development-approach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The agile software development approach consists of working through a development project as a series of short, focused cycles. Often called &amp;ldquo;iterations&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;sprints&amp;rdquo;. After each iteration, the team evaluates the results and adjusts the plan as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The high level concept of Agile is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliver value first:&lt;/strong&gt;
Features are built in the order of business value, ensuring the most valuable work is completed first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintaining high quality:&lt;/strong&gt;
Quality is a top priority throughout the development process, not just at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agile Is a Small Idea</title>
      <link>https://agiletechies.com/posts/agile-is-a-small-idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>rajesh@duggalmail.com (Raj Duggal)</author>
      <guid>https://agiletechies.com/posts/agile-is-a-small-idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Robert C. Martin says that Agile is a small idea about the small problem of small programming teams doing small things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Agile is not a big idea about the big problem of big programming teams doing big things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big things don’t get done by big teams; big things get done by the collaboration of many small teams doing many small things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help popularize this, back in the early 2000s, the idea was given a name. “Agile.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
